```
// JEN_SYKES

// C.V

// 2020

// -----

General

DOB 20.01.1986
Resident: Glasgow (Scotland, UK)

// ----

Contact

Website: https://j3nsykes.github.io/
Email: j3nsykes@gmail.com
Telephone: +44 7291063494
Github: https://github.com/j3nsykes
```

Biography

Jen Sykes is an artist, designer and educator based in Glasgow, Scotland. Having graduated from the MFA in Computational Arts at Goldsmiths University of London in 2012, her work spans creative computer programming, sculpture and electronic hardware designs often connecting the physical analog and digital worlds. Her research focuses on using computer related materials to narrate qualities which normally lay dormant, invisible to the human eye. Her research has led her to develop her own circuits and hardware as well as frequently fabricating sensors, interfaces and interactive installations for other artists and designers.

// -----

Employment

2021	Creative Coding Associate Professor, Royal Academy of Art, Copenhagen
2017 - Present	Lecturer in Physical Computing and Interactive Prototyping, Glasgow School of Art
2020	Creative Machine Learning, Visiting Lecturer, Umeå University (with Andreas Refsgaard)
2020	Creative Machine Learning, Visiting Lecturer, Copenhagen Institute Interaction Design (with Andreas Refsgaard)
2020	Interactive Prototyping, Workshop Lead, LEGO, Bilund.
2020	Creative Machine Learning, Visiting Lecturer, Copenhagen Institute Interaction Design (with Andreas Refsgaard)
2019	Creative Coding and Machine Learning, Workshop Lead, Normally Studio, London

2019	Creative Machine Learning, Visiting Lecturer, Copenhagen Institute Interaction Design (with Andreas Refsgaard)
2017 - 2019	Input Output: Creative Coding, Workshop Lead, Glasgow Sculpture Studios
2015 - 2017	Interactive Prototyping Teaching Assistant, Glasgow School of Art
2014 - 2015	Digital Designer, The Hidden Gardens, Glasgow
2014- 2015	Front-end Web Design, Social Firms Scotland, Glasgow
2014	Front-end Web Design, Sinewave Design, Edinburgh
2009 – 2012	Creative Workshop Lead, The Hidden Gardens, Glasgow
//	
Education	
2020 - onwards	PhD (part-time), Creative Computing Institute, University of the Arts London (UAL)
2012 - 2014	MFA Computational Studio Art (Distinction), Goldsmiths University of London
2005 - 2009	BA Hons Environmental Art (1st Class), Glasgow School of Art
//	
Research	
2020 — onwards	Functional Mistakes; a path towards expressive, non-linear material approaches to physical computing, Creative Coding Institute, UAL, London
2017	Enterface 2017, Rapid APi research participant, Porto, Portugal

Selected Works and Collaborations

2021	New Forms of Togetherness, Al Residency mentor, NEON Festival and the Geothe Institute.
2020	Robots in Residence, in collaboration with Tom Krasny, Geothe Institute, Glasgow
2020	The Art Museum, in collaboration with Andreas Refsgaard, SMK - Danish National Art Gallery, Copenhagen
2020	FlipDot, Duncan Campbell, Glasgow International festival, Glasgow
2019	Let the Music Play On and On and On, with Carrie Skinner, Center for Contemporary Art, Glasgow
2019	Furniture Music with Yuri Suzuki, Sonica, Cryptic, Glasgow
2018	Portal, with Robbie Thompson, Cryptic, Glasgow

2018	NeuralPS, Places You've Never Been, A.I Art, Montreal, Canada
2018	On the Waves of Air there is Magic Out There, with Carrie Skinner, Glasgow International Festival, Glasgow
2018	iOS and Android App front-end development, Co-designing tools for end of life care for people with dementia, University of Glasgow and Glasgow School of Art Research Team.
2017	setup(), Project Room Gallery, Glasgow
2017	Listening Benches, BBC Glasgow, London, Cardiff and Belfast
2016	Objects of Domestication, Line of Sight, Reid Gallery, Glasgow
2016	Choose Your Friends Wisely, Line of Sight, Reid Gallery, Glasgow
2016	Radio Transmissions, with Kimberly O'Neil, Telfer Gallery, Glasgow
2015	Museum for an Imagined City, SOIL, Seattle